Nathan L. Whetten Papers 1997.0131
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Nathan L. Whetten Papers
1932-1998.
1997.0131
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
1.0 Linear feet
Nathan L. Whetten began his career at the University of Connecticut 1932 as a statistician in the Sociology Department, then located at the Experimental Station. In 1940, Whetten was offered the position of Dean of the Graduate School, a position he held until 1970/1971. Dr. Whetten died in 1984.
Whetten, Nathan L. (Nathan Laselle).
Biography
Nathan L. Whetten began his career at the University of Connecticut 1932 as a statistician in the Sociology Department, then located at the Experiment Station. By 1935, he had been promoted to Assistant Profess of Rural Sociology, making full Professor in 1938. In 1940, Whetten was offered the position of Dean of the Graduate School, a position he held until 1970/1971. He traveled and lectured in Mexico and Latin America, publishing a book on Guatmala, Guatamala: The Land and The People. Dr. Whetten died in 1984.
Scope and Content
The collection includes Whetten's graduate thesis, some correspondence, reprints of articles he authored and co-authored, and files from his UConn related responsibilities.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Unknown.
Administrative Records.; Correspondence.; Educator.; Educators—Connecticut.; Guatemala.; Latin America.; Mexico.; Minutes.; Notes.; Photographs.; Publications.; Sociologist.; Sociology—Study and teaching—Connecticut.; Universities and colleges—Administration.; University of Connecticut—Faculty.
- Series I: Papers, 1932-1970
  - Article reprints (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Certificates (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Guatamala book jacket (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lectures— South America (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Newsletter (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Presidential Selection Advisory Committee (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Printed materials (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Student thesis (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - UConn name change official documents (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Whetten thesis— Harvard University (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Series II: 2012 Addition, 1940-1998
  - Newspaper articles, 1940-1998 (Box 3)
  - Biographical sketch, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Curriculum vitae, 1956 (Box 3)
  - List of Publictions, 1958 (Box 3)
  - History of the Graduate School, 1957 (Box 3)
  - UConn Club, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Commencement address, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Personal, 1946-1964 (Box 3)
  - 75th Anniversary Celebration, 1956-1957 (Box 3)
  - Annual report, 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Annual report of the Dean, 1964-1974 (Box 3)